

Danial Aswad Bin Ahmad Fazlan

Software Engineer

1993 Malaysian Manialaswad

Summary

Graduate software engineer specialised in digitalisation and software architecture. My expertise is in guiding and improving business approach through digital transformation with experience working in the European and Asia Pacific market. My current role as **Business Analyst in a multinational IT company based in France** has provided me with compelling skills in communicating with clients, conducting analysis on business initiatives and managing software development operations from as early as gathering requirements to delivering software features to stakeholders.

Work Experiences

Business Analyst

Amadeus IT Group, France | 2018 - Present

Responsible for conducting business analysis, formulating project specification, negotiating project timeline and performing market research for software projects/developments which directly impacts Sales and Operations.

- Successfully delivered the first rail multi-inventory reservation platform consisting of numerous rail providers across
 Europe and also fully integrated to the Global Distribution System (GDS) leading to a significant increase in ticket sales
 and securing new clients in the form of travel agencies.
- Performed project presentation and created training materials for the implementation team for every new product enhancement allowing a successful continuous integration and continuous delivery (CI/CD) process
- Engineered a new software testing tool using Python which has optimised test script writing from 1-2 day(s) to 3-4 hours. Influenced and trained the implementation team to apply the tool resulted in a significant decrease of production issues, saving thousands of dollars for the company

Software Engineer Apprentice

Amadeus IT Group, France | 2017 - 2018

- Lead the development of an intelligent orchestrator application which significantly shortened the duration of implementing a new rail inventory
- Conducted a comprehensive research in shopping and reservation trend from CRM (Salesforce) application to build a customer centric product
- Created the recommendation algorithm in Python with Scikit-learn and Tensorflow, to predict user behaviour and deliver suggestion with 90% accuracy rate
- Formulated API user guidelines and delivered API trainings to the department, increasing the productivity of the product development process

Software Developer Intern

Accenture Solutions, Malaysia | 2017

- Guaranteed the product meets customer business initiatives through continuous review meeting and product delivery
- Tested and debugged issues on a mobile specific application on both iOS and Android operating system
- Designed and implemented in-app multi-language support
- Optimised code design to solve performance issues and to improve development process

Educations

Engineering Degree & Master's in Computer Science | 2015 - 2018

- École d'Ingénieur Polytech Nice Sophia Antipolis, France, specialised in Software Architecture
- Université de Nice Sophia Antipolis, France, specialised in Computer
 Foundation and Engineering

Higher National Diploma in Technology | 2013 - 2015

Université de Nice Sophia Antipolis, France, **specialised in Network and Telecommunication**

Skills

English | Malay | French Python | Java | JavaScript Jira | Confluence | Git

Interests

Artificial Intelligence | Big Data | IoT | Sports

Volunteer Experiences

Event Coordinator | Polytech Nice Open Day | 2017

Event Organiser | Polytech Career Fair | 2017